A Guide to the Papers of the Slaughter Family, 1864-1929
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Slaughter Family 1864-1929
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
1006
This collection consists of 680 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library by Charles Slaughter of Charlottesville, Virginia, on December 1, 1940.
Scope and Content Information
The first American ancestor of the Slaughter family apparently arrived in Virginia in 1620. The family prospered through many generations as landowners, soldiers, professionals and academics, and public servants. Today members of the extended Slaughter family inhabit virtually every state in the union, yet the family has been able to locate and maintain contact with its various branches through a voluminous correspondence. This collection of ca. 680 items contains correspondence about genealogical issues, mostly between the various family members and Judge William A. Slaughter or Albert Slaughter, as well as myriad genealogical lists, anecdotal material, records, and versions of the family history.
Contents List
- Correspondence 1864-1866, 1890-1898 (Box 1)
  Although some of the correspondence deals with timely family matters and business, the vast majority of the letters relate information about family genealogy. Distant relatives write to William A. Slaughter or Alfred Slaughter to ask the specific place in the genealogy of their ancestors, or conversely to inform them on some point of family genealogy or family lore.
- Correspondence 1901-1904 (Box 1)
- Correspondence 1905-1908 (Box 1)
- Correspondence 1909-1918 (Box 1)
- Correspondence 1920-1929 (Box 1)
- Correspondence 1930-1939 (Box 1)
- Correspondence n.d. (Box 1)
- Correspondence: post cards 1903-1934 (Box 1)
- Legal Documents 1656-1898 (Box 1)
  The folder includes copies of 18th century contracts for an indenture and a bill of sale for slaves, copies of 17th and 18th century Slaughters' wills, a passport issued in 1889 and various certificates.
- Personal Accounts n.d. (Box 1)
  This includes three pages of accounts for sewing materials and an account of mortgage interests
- Printed Materials 1900-1939 (Box 1)
  This includes wedding, birth, and funeral announcements and business cards for Slaughters or extended family. Advertisements for books pertaining to Virginia genealogies have also been collected.
- Miscellaneous: poems, news clippings n.d. (Box 1)
  As well as obituaries and articles on various Slaughters, there are also included articles of genealogical and general interest.
- Family Coat of Arms: Smith of Totnes 1909 (Box 1)
- Photographs n.d. (Box 1)
  Most are unidentified, but are obviously Slaughter family members.
- Photographs n.d. (Box 1)
- Genealogical Papers: 17th century 1870-1935 (Box 2)
  These include, for each century, bits of information about the various branches and members of the extended Slaughter family, anecdotal material, and lists.
- Genealogical Papers: 18th century 1870-1935 (Box 2)
- Genealogical Papers: 19th century 1860-1939 (Box 2)
- Genealogical Papers: 20th century 1900-1939 (Box 2)
- Genealogical Papers: general 17th-20th century, and collateral families. n.d. (Box 2)
- Genealogical Papers: genealogy charts of 17th and 18th century branches of Slaughters 1890-1930 (Box 2)
- Genealogical Records: Books 1617-1925 1920s (Box 2)
- Genealogical Records: Books 1720-1920 1920s (Box 2)
- Genealogical Records: Books 1620-1930 1930s (Box 2)
  One of the books is an autographed manuscript compilation of Slaughter family history entitled Genealogy of the Slaughter Family, presumably authored by William A. Slaughter.
- Slaughter family genealogy from 1650 to the birth of William A. Slaughter in 1885 1930s, Bound Volume (Box 2)
- Genealogical Charts of the Slaughter family, especially descendants of Robert and Samuel Slaughter n.d. (Box 2)
- Daguerreotypes n.d. (Box 2)
  Woman seated at table and small girl with "ghost" reflection.